actually is the power of the people's
vote and I think the people should use
it to vote for okay so in this series of
videos as I said in the introduction I'm
gonna try and make the case in more
detail for none of the above as a
serious political campaign there's going
to be three possibly four of these in
total in this particular video I want to
explore the potential that none of the
above has for inclusivity and
unification of people from a wide range
of very disparate walks of life and once
again there's a few strands to this so
the first one is unifying activists
around the world and I use both of these
words in their broadest possible sense
so by activists what I mean is not
necessarily people who are out on the
street with placards or blocking gates
or whatever it might be but people who
are working in some way or another to
try and make life better for people and
so you know just to give a very few
examples you've got people working to
alleviate trial poverty anti-war
protesters environmental protesters
people looking to live communal lives
you know sustainable communal lives AIDS
and Refugee workers all around the world
just just to give a handful of examples
and Chai's are Charles Eisenstein in his
work points to this idea that all of
these people are in fact on the same
side these are individuals and small
groups of people working to help others
basically and there are potentially
hundreds of millions of these people
around the world but because you know
each individual or small group is doing
their own thing they have very different
voices they're all campaigning for or
working for very different things even
within a particular activist community
like I mentioned in the first video I'm
part of the resource-based economics
movement and even within that there are
dozens possibly even hundreds of
individuals and small groups and a
couple of larger groups working in their
own particular way towards bringing
resource-based economics into the world
but they disagree on how best to go
about doing that and you know some think
it's about education others think it's
about political campaigning other think
others think it's about creating the
systems and you know working
independently of the existing structures
and institutions and they kind of fall
out with each other even though they're
all on the same side two things to this
all of these arguments go away under
none of the above because they can all
agree that well whatever particular
route we think says bring it to public
awareness no to remember is all about
creating a forum in which ideas can be
discussed and so it accomplishes that
it's also something that can run us
alongside and does not conflict with
what people are already doing so all of
those people that I mentioned before
could continue doing what they're doing
because that's what they care about but
they could also campaign for and
manifest and convince other people to
vote for none of the above
you know I'm voting none of the above
because and this is in recognition of
the fact that all of these people all of
these campaigners all of these activists
all of these aid workers are only having
to do what they do because of the
shortcomings of our of the systems that
we use to organize ourselves and so
things like extreme poverty when there's
plenty of food to feed everybody
things like millions of people dying of
AIDS when there's plenty of medication
to treat everybody things like the
answers to the continued unsustainable
extraction of resources year in year out
getting more and more intensive doing
more and more damaged all of these
things are forms of pollution emitted by
our systems into the rest of the world
and I'm going to go into this in a lot
more detail in a future video but the
point anyway the overarching point of
this first bit is that having all of
these disparate groups all of these
disparate individuals weakens the
overall message that this is not working
we need something different we need
fundamental re-evaluations we need
fundamental structural changes to the
way that we do things I think it's also
worth mentioning extinction rebellion
and this is a very recent example of
successful popular movement successful
in the sense that it got a lot of play
in the media a lot of attend
and they did two things very well
firstly they had an excellent
organizational structure where you know
when once people have been recruited to
the movement they had a sense of ongoing
involvement through training sessions
and simulations and education and so on
and so on but even more importantly than
that they had a single message that
everybody got behind you know that the
government needs to do something
immediately about climate change and
these are our three demands and that
everybody was on exactly the same page
and so I think it's worth noting as a
recent example the power of a single
message rather than a disparate one lots
of people lots of different concerns the
second part is this I mean this varies
significantly from country to country
but you know let's say for the sake of
argument that some 30 percent of people
don't vote at all it elections and I
think it's reasonable to assume that in
large part that is because they just
can't get behind any of the candidates
and I mean I I know lots and lots of
people who do vote but they are not
particularly happy about who they're
voting for is just the choices they're
presented with is nothing there to get
excited about and so I think for all of
these kinds of people that none of the
above again could be an umbrella to
under which these people could stand
because it makes the vote makes the
remote vote meaningful again you know
instead of wasting a vote on somebody
that you hate or wasting your vote by
not voting at all or wasting your vote
on some party who in a constituency
based system has absolutely no chance of
getting a representative in Parliament
you could be part of something bigger
something meaningful something that
could bring about actual radical
long-term change so I think this could
be very exciting to a lot of people and
could bring a lot of people into the
none of the above forum if you like and
if it is also used as a place in which
the problems that faces can be honestly
and openly and properly examined for the
first time and where solutions radical
ones really you know out there ones can
be at least considered and used as the
starting point to develop things that
are more realistic from you know this
this could be very exciting to a lot of
people and then the third part of this
is that I think none of the above could
actually be the beginning of
healing for us as a society I mean I
think most people would agree that we
are a seriously fractured and divided
and at war with itself society at the
moment and despite what I said earlier
about people falling out about little
things even when they're all on the same
team I think coming together under
something as simple and direct and
powerful as none of the above and having
that be successful could lay the ground
for the kind of collaboration which at
the moment we simply don't see in the
world and don't get me wrong I'm not
under playing the difficulty of this
huge conversation that needs to be had
is going to be unbelievably hard and
there's going to be people arguing and
falling out with each other all the time
all the time all the time however that
doesn't mean that we shouldn't be having
it we must have it it's absolutely
essential and yes it may be chaotic and
confusing for a while but in the long
run this is the only way where we're
going to create a world where
environmental activists are no longer
necessary because we are no longer
abusing the environment we're anti-war
protestors are no longer necessary
because we no longer find it necessary
to go to war with each other where
poverty workers are no longer needed
because there is no more poverty and so
that's about it for this video there are
probably two maybe three more to come
but for now thank you very much for
listening and I think the people should
use it to vote for
[Applause]